Guide to the Associated Students of Central Washington University, Files 1925-1989 (bulk 1945-1965)
Central Washington University Archives and Special Collections
Associated Students of Central Washington University, Files
1925-2016
Central Washington University, Archives and Special Collections 400 E University Way Ellensburg, WA 98926 (509) 963-1717 http://www.lib.cwu.edu/Archives-Special-Collections archive@cwu.edu
RG008-06-51
Associated Students of Central Washington University
4.5 cubic foot 8 letter-sized document cases
The Associated Students of Central Washington University Miscellaneous Files contain information and publications on student activities, student clubs and campus events as well as student government information, 1925-1989.
Historical Note
The Associated Student Body of Washington State Normal School (WSNS) was established in March of 1908 to educate WSNS students in parliamentary procedures during weekly meetings. In 1910, meetings produced proposals to manage student affairs as a student government organization. Eventually, the student body developed into a student government and was renamed the Associated Students of Central Washington State College and later Associated Students of Central Washington University.
The student activities recreation series consists of recreation schedules for student sports and activities for several calendar years at Central Washington University (and its predecessors), which include both intramural sports and non-sport related activities. The student club portion of this collection includes information on activities in student clubs, including the Associated Women Students and news clippings regarding Central Washington University’s now defunct Greek system. There are also files regarding faculty and administration and their activities including the bizarre but much coveted Snarf Award, awarded to the most bizarre and academically sadistic teacher of the year.
The campus events portion of this collection includes information on Homecoming, Senior Days, Parents Day and Sweecy Day as well as several other campus events such as New Student Week and Religious Emphasis week. All files contain news clippings with pictures of the events as they happened.
Central Washington University began as the Washington State Normal School in 1891. In 1937, the school was rechristened the Central Washington College of Education. In 1961, the school became Central Washington State College and, finally, in 1977, Central Washington University.
Alphabetical and chronological
Open to the public for educational research
See RG067-06-73, Office of Alumni Relations, Records, for other materials relating to student life and activities at Central Washington University.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Ellensburg (Wash.)
Central Washington University--History
Colleges and Universities; Washington (State)
- Activities--Associated Women Students, 1939-1969 (Box-folder 1-1)
- Activities--Dining and Housing, 1941-1945 (Box-folder 1-2)
- Activities--Homecoming, 1925 (Box-folder 1-3)
- Activities--Homecoming, 1926-1929 (Box-folder 1-4)
- Activities--Homecoming, 1931-1937 (Box-folder 1-5)
- Activities--Homecoming, 1940-1949 (Box-folder 1-6)
- Activities--Homecoming, 1950-1959 (Box-folder 1-7)
- Activities--Homecoming, 1960-1969 (Box-folder 1-8)
- Activities--Homecoming, 1970-1977 (Box-folder 1-9)
- Activities--Homecoming (News clippings), 1948-1959 (Box-folder 1-10)
- Activities--Miscellaneous events (speech clinic), 1939-1940 (Box-folder 1-11)
- Activities--Miscellaneous events, 1941-1998 (Box-folder 1-12)
- Activities--Music and drama programs, 1942-2003 (Box-folder 1-13)
- Activities--News Clippings, 1933-1948 (Box-folder 1-14)
- Activities--News Clippings, 1948-1953 (Box-folder 2-1)
- Activities--News Clippings, 1954-1956 (Box-folder 2-2)
- Activities--News Clippings, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 2-3)
- Activities--Parents Day, 1936-1995 (Box-folder 2-4)
- Activities--Politics, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 2-5)
- Activities--Recreation Schedules and Bulletins, 1928-1959 (Box-folder 2-6)
- Activities--Recreation Schedules and Bulletins, 1960-1964 (Box-folder 2-7)
- Activities--Recreation Schedules and Bulletins, 1965-1979 (Box-folder 2-8)
- Activities--Religious Emphasis Week, 1953-1957 (Box-folder 2-9)
- Activities--Senior Days, 1948-1965 (Box-folder 2-10)
- Activities--Student Government, 1945-1964 (Box-folder 2-11)
- Activities--Student Government, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 3-1)
- Activities--Student Government, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 3-2)
- Activities--Sweecy Day, 1948-1968 (Box-folder 3-3)
- Activities--Various, Faculty and Administration, 1941-1970 (Box-folder 3-4)
- Activities--Various, Greek Organizations, 1946-1964 (Box-folder 3-5)
- Activities--Various, New Student Week, 1944-1970 (Box-folder 3-6)
- Activities--Various, Religious Groups, 1962-1966 (Box-folder 3-7)
- Activities--Various, Student Model UN, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 3-8)
- Activities--Various, Student Organization Directory, 1936-1970 (Box-folder 3-9)
- Activities--Various Organizations, 1949-1963 (Box-folder 3-10)
- Activities--Various Organizations, 1963-2003 (Box-folder 3-11)
- Partners, Student Union Rec Center, SURC Guidelines, 2008-; RG 008-21-06 (Box-folder 4-1)
- Military Concern, 2006-; RG 008-21-06 (Box-folder 4-2)
- Emergency Management Task Force, Identity Theft, 2005-2007; RG 008-21-06 (Box-folder 4-3)
- Student Union Board, SUB, 1999-2000; RG 008-21-06 (Box-folder 4-4)
- Recreation Advisory Board, Polices, 2012-2013; RG 008-21-06 (Box-folder 4-5)
- Liqour Control Board, Policies, 2001-2005; RG 008-21-06 (Box-folder 4-6)
- Excel, Discovery Advisory Board, 2009-; RG 008-21-06 (Box-folder 4-7)
- Tuition Waiver Board, 2013-2014; RG 008-21-06 (Box-folder 4-8)
- Campus Developmental Committee, 2012-2013; RG 008-21-06 (Box-folder 4-9)
- Student Union Rec Center Project, 2004-2005; RG 008-21-06 (Box-folder 4-10)
- Student Academic Senate, 2010-2011; RG 008-21-06 (Box-folder 5-1)
- Student Academic Senate part 2, 2010-2011; RG 008-21-06 (Box-folder 5-2)
- Student Academic Senate, 2011-2012; RG 008-21-06 (Box-folder 5-3)
- Student Academic Senate, 2012-2013; RG 008-21-06 (Box-folder 5-4)
- Student Academic Senate, 2013-2014; RG 008-21-06 (Box-folder 5-5)
- Student Academic Senate, 2014-2015; RG 008-21-06 (Box-folder 6-1)
- Student Academic Senate, 2015-2016; RG 008-21-06 (Box-folder 6-2)
- Constitution and Bylaws, 2008-; RG008-06-51 (Box-folder 7-1)
- Design Phase Submittal SUB, Rec, 2003-; RG008-06-51 (Box-folder 7-2)
- Constitution and Bylaws, 2009-; RG008-06-51 (Box-folder 7-3)
- Board of Directors Agendas, 2012-2013; RG008-06-51 (Box-folder 7-4)
- Kelsy's Documents, 2005-2017; RG008-06-51 (Box-folder 7-5)
- Rob Lane Folder, 2012-2013; RG008-06-51 (Box-folder 7-6)
- Universtity Recreation Advisory Board, 2006-2014; RG008-06-51 (Box-folder 7-7)
- Specifics and Fee Facts,SUB, Health and Counseling Fees, 2002-2006; RG008-06-51 (Box-folder 7-8)
- Security Committee, Surveillance, 2007-2008; RG008-06-51 (Box-folder 7-9)
- Planning Details, Schedules, 2011-2012; RG008-06-51 (Box-folder 8-1)
- Recreation Advisory Board, 2013-; RG008-06-51 (Box-folder 8-2)
- Sources of Stress in College Students, 2011-; RG008-06-51 (Box-folder 8-3)
- Student Union Recreation Center, 2008-2009; RG008-06-51 (Box-folder 8-4)
- Determinationfor CWU's Renovations and Additions, 2009-; RG008-06-51 (Box-folder 8-5)
- Shared Governance, 2012-; RG008-06-51 (Box-folder 8-6)
- Student Union Advisory Board, Members, 2012-2013; RG008-06-51 (Box-folder 8-7)
- CWU Building Guide, CWU Master Plan, 2005-2006; RG008-06-51 (Box-folder 8-8)
- Housing and Food Services Fund, 2000-2005; RG008-06-51 (Box-folder 8-9)
- Correspondence, Response to Public Comment, 2005-; RG008-06-51 (Box-folder 8-10)